

vigneshkannaiyan.official@gmail.com, 9952209682

Summary:

Versatile Software Developer with experience in the software industry. Demonstrated excellent skills in NodeJs, ExpressJs, NestJs, ReactJs, Prisma ORM, MongoDB, My SQL, Sequelize Js, JavaScript ,ReactJs, Microservices, Jenkins, docker, kubernetes, podman and SIEM tools. True team player with strengths in adaptability and accuracy.

Also fast learner and able to adapt myself in a new technology or a new programming language. *Interested in contributing my expertise in front end development and deployments* .

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

IBM India Pvt. Ltd - Kochi, Kerala November 2023 to April 2024

Project Title: Cloud Pak For Data (CP4D)

Description:

IBM Cloud Pak® for Data is a modular set of integrated software components for data analysis, organization and management. It is available for self-hosting, or as a managed service on IBM Cloud & others. Break down data silos, Access data across business silos, on premises and in clouds, without moving the data. Keep data private and secure, Universally safeguard data usage with privacy and usage policy enforcement across all data. Empower all data consumers, Enable users of all skill levels to access trusted data with tailored interfaces (Code, Canvas, No Code).

Role:

- Backend codes are developed using Golang and the front end is on React Js (This is specified to the module which we handled).
- Writing the React Js code for the given designs and changes.
- Deploying the build in the docker using jenkins.
- Integrated with various SIEM tools such as Splunk, Mezmo, Papertrails for tracking and monitoring all kinds of security events.
- Also forwarded the logs to Kafka to check, tracking and monitoring all kinds of security events with and without TLS.

Software Developer

Mobile Programming Inc Pvt. Ltd - Chennai, TamilNadu May 2022 to November 2023

Project Title: Adani One (Adani Digital Labs)

Description:

Adanione is a product where a user can book air tickets, train tickets, hotel stay, travel packages, cabs, porter service, duty free items and also a meet and greet service name Pranaam all modes of payments are integrated withJusPay. The user will be rewarded by reward points and various coupon codes. The main scope of the product is to give the user unparalleled experience of travel and lifestyle across the nation.

Role:

- Backend codes are developed using NodeJs with the framework NestJs.
- Developed database integration in MongoDB using Prisma ORM and used BullMQ for jobs and schedulers.
- Writing the complex calculation algorithms for the payments, coupons and reward points.
- Writing the swagger file using nest js/swagger in the controller files.

- Integrated with various third party api's for the microservices for all the available services in the application.
- Databases used are MongoDB, Prisma ORM and payment gateway is JusPay.

Project Title: Market 360 (eClerx)

Description:

Market 360 is the application where we can track the movement of sales, stock, inventory movement of the products. The users and providers have separate portals in the application. The outlets can track their sales and stock and inventory movements of each product. Likewise the product manufacturers also track their sales, stock

and inventory movements. Yearly, Monthly, Weekly and daily movements can be tracked by various graphs and filters like graphs, pie charts and so on.

Role:

- Backend codes are developed using NodeJs using the ExpressJs framework.
- Developed database integration in MongoDB.
- Writing the complex calculation aggregation queries respective to the requirements.

Software Developer

OASYS Cybernetics Pvt. Ltd - Chennai, TamilNadu March 2021 to May 2022

Project Title: HMIS (Health Management Information System)

Description:

A web application for monitoring the Hospital details such as patients information, doctor's information, hospital staff's information, assets information, inventory information etc. Based on the roles given to users, their access in the application also varies. Main scope of this application is to reduce the time consumption occurs in this department. Not only doctors and patients information, the dealers and manufacturers, drivers, launderers and who are all associated with the hospital environment also get benefits by this application. This project is currently live for the Government of TamilNadu and Government of Maharashtra.

Role:

- Writing backend codes using NodeJs which performs the CRUD operations, bulk data upload and download.
- Developed database integration in MySql using Sequelize. Js and also in MongoDB.
- Writing the complex queries for the database to get the data in respective searches (In both MySql and MongoDB).
- Creating unit test cases for all the api's in the backend using the node module mocha, chai.
- Writing the swagger documentation file using the node module swagger.
- Setting up the swagger documentation file for ws02.
- Database used are MongoDB and MySql (Sequelize js)

Software Developer

Comorin Consulting Services- Bengaluru, Karnataka Aug 2020 to October 2020

Project Title: CPOS

Description:

A web application for recruiting the new candidates. Based on the various levels of hierarchies in the organization the recruitment process of the candidate flows through the application. Initially a candidate will come in as a New Candidate and his flow ends as Selected Candidate or Rejected candidates based on the decision of the designated person in the hierarchy. And the candidates who are all put on hold are also referred to in the future.

Role:

- Creating unit test cases for all the api's in the backend using the node module mocha ,chai .
- Writing the swagger documentation file using the node module swagger.
- Setting up the test server using ngrok and assisted the integration with the frontend (Angular Js).
- Writing backend codes using NodeJs which performs the user profile validation, report generation, bulk data upload and download.
- Developed database integration using MongoDB.

Project Title: Cable Pay

Description:

A web application for monitoring the internet services provided by the organization. There we can track what type of connection providing, type of payment method, location of the client who got the service, admin details, employee details, customer details, distributor details, invoice, billing history, collected amount, pre payment amount, pending

amount , plan validity, existing plans, plan renewals, changes of plans everything can be tracked and monitored in this web application.

Role:

- Creating unit test cases for all the api's in the backend using the node module mocha ,chai .
- Writing the swagger documentation file using the node module swagger.
- Setting up the test server using ngrok and assisted the integration with the frontend (Angular Js).
- Writing backend codes using NodeJs which performs the user profile validation, report generation, bulk data upload and download.
- Developed database integration using MongoDB.

Agilite Group Technologies Pvt Ltd - Hyderabad, Telangana July 2018 to June 2020

Project Title: Tool and Die Management

Description:

A web application for the storage and analysis of 'tools', 'machines' which are all engaged in producing the 'components' which are the end products of Industry. There are various hierarchies available from organization head to store-keeper and each user is restricted with certain priorities in application. The ultimate part of the application is the 'Blockchain' which differs it from other applications.

Role:

- Writing backend codes using NodeJs which performs the user profile validation, report generation, bulk data upload and download.
- Developed database integration using MongoDB.
- Created Blockchain network using Hyperledger Composer and Hyperledger Fabric which provides the security and trust over the peer networks.
- Report generation is done using TIBCO Jaspersoft. In this we can download the individual or bulk data in pdf or excel format as per the user's wish.

Project Title: Bunkering Solutions

Description:

Bunkering is supplying a ship with fuel, lubricating oils, and portable water which usually happens in a port. The navy and a number of companies already bunker at sea; it saves a lot of time and money. But bunkering in ports also causes port congestion, because other vessels have to wait for a berthing place when a vessel is bunkering. Bunkering in sea can

be complicated in bad weather conditions, so we developed a system in which we can monitor the process of bunkering. And also this can reduce the risk of port congestion. Using this we can track and monitor the availability of the ports.

Role:

- Writing backend codes using NodeJs which performs the user profile validation, report generation, bulk data upload and download.
- Developed database integration using MongoDB.
- Created separate user profiles for the flexibility of the users, email validation and password validation are done using nodemailer and encrypt, bcrypt respectively.
- Report generation is done using TIBCO Jaspersoft. In this we can download the individual or bulk data in pdf or excel
 format as per the user's wish.

Technologies Used

- NodeJs
- NestJs
- ReactJs
- Prisma
- JusPay
- Javascript
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- · Sequelize Js
- · Express Js
- Jenkins
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- SIEM Tools
- Kafka
- JSON
- Rest API
- Blockchain
- · TIBCO Jaspersoft
- Ubuntu (OS)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology

Anna University 2014 to 2018

HSLC (12th Pass)

M.Najappa Chettiar Matric Hr.Sec School August 2012 to March 2014

SKILLS / IT SKILLS

- Node js
- React js
- MongoDB
- Prisma
- My Sql
- Sequelizer
- JavaScript
- Docker
- Kafka
- SIEM Tools
- TIBCO Jaspersoft
- Postman API
- Talend Open Studio

ONLINE PROFILE

Linked In - http://linkedin.com/in/vignesh-kannaiyan-b40ab718b

Portfolio - https://vigneshkannaiyanportfolio.netlify.app/